<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Kind Companion</string>
    <string name="note_entry_header">Note Entry</string>
    <string name="reminder_button">Store as \n Reminder</string>
    <string name="vault_button">Store in \n Vault</string>
    <string name="void_button">Send into \n the void</string>
    <string name="note_entry_hint">Enter your note…</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->

    <string name="note_entry_title_hint">Title</string>
    <string name="new_note">New Note</string>
    <string name="firstMainButton">Get it off my chest</string>
    <string name="secondMainButton">Deal With Anxiety</string>
    <string name="thirdMainButton">Useful Information</string>
    <string name="frontPageWelcomeMessage">Welcome to Kind Companion!</string>
    <string name="fourthMainButton">Reminders</string>
    <string name="fifthMainButton">Vault</string>
    <string name="sixthMainButton">Settings</string>
    <string name="store_note">Store as Note</string>
    <string name="store_vault">Store in Vault</string>
    <string name="send_void">Send into the void</string>
    <string name="burn_thoughts">Burn your thoughts away</string>
    <string name="text_size_small">Text Size Small</string>
    <string name="text_size_large">Text Size Large</string>
    <string name="save">SAVE</string>
    <string name="couldnt_be_saved">The note couldn\'t be saved.</string>
    <!-- Preference Titles -->
    <string name="messages_header">Messages</string>
    <string name="sync_header">Sync</string>

    <!-- Messages Preferences -->
    <string name="signature_title">Your signature</string>
    <string name="reply_title">Default reply action</string>

    <!-- Sync Preferences -->
    <string name="sync_title">Sync email periodically</string>
    <string name="attachment_title">Download incoming attachments</string>
    <string name="attachment_summary_on">Automatically download attachments for incoming emails
    </string>
    <string name="attachment_summary_off">Only download attachments when manually requested</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">SettingsActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_useful_resources">UsefulResourcesActivity</string>
    <string name="tab_text_1">Tab 1</string>
    <string name="tab_text_2">Tab 2</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoCredits">Information taken from https://www.psycom.net/bookstore.anxiety.html</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoHeaderOne">Generalised Anxiety Disorder</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoTextOne">If you find yourself in constant worry over anything and everything in your life, even when there should be no cause for concern, you might be suffering from Generalized Anxiety Disorder.</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoTextTwo">Generalized Anxiety Disorder is one of the most common anxiety disorders. While it can occur at any point of life, the most common points of onset occur between childhood and middle age. \nIf you are a woman, you are twice as likely to suffer from Generalized Anxiety Disorder than men.</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoSubtextOne">Generalized Anxiety Disorder is different than having a phobia about something in the sense that people with GAD have an uneasy feeling about life in general. \nOften associated with feelings of dread or unease, you are in a state of constant worry over everything. There is no “off” switch. \nIf you are suffering from Generalized Anxiety Disorder, you are experiencing a constant state of worry – and you cannot avoid it, because life, in general, is causing you anxiety.</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoSubtextTwo">Studies have shown that if you are living with Generalized Anxiety Disorder, you are more likely to also suffer from other mental health issues and ailments. \nCommon conditions that are associated with Generalized Anxiety Disorder include depression(https://www.psycom.net/depression.central.html), irritable bowel syndrome, stress, attention deficit hyperactivity disorder(https://www.psycom.net/adult-adhd/), and substance abuse(https://www.psycom.net/depression.central.substance.html).</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoHeaderTwo">Symptoms</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoTextThree">Some of the symptoms of GAD are:</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoSubtextThree">• Perpetual state of constant worry\n• Inability to relax or enjoy quiet time\n• Muscle tightness or body aches\n• Feeling tense\n• Avoidance of stressful situations\n• Difficulty concentrating or focusing on things\n• No tolerance for uncertainty – needing to know what is going to happen and how it is going to happen\n• Constant feelings of dread or apprehension\n• Feeling overwhelmed and avoiding things or situations because of it\n• Intrusive thoughts of things that cause you to worry – even when you try to stop thinking about them\n• Feeling like you can’t control your emotions and constant worry – nothing you do helps you to relax\n• Not being able to sleep at all or to sleep well because you are in a constant state of worry\n• Feeling jumpy, on edge, or restless\n• Stomach upset – including nausea and diarrhea\n• Fatiguing easily\n• Heart palpitations – feeling like your heart is racing\n• Trembles or shakes\n• Sweating and dry mouth\n• Having difficulty breathing and/or feeling like you are choking\n• Feeling lightheaded or dizzy\n• Cold chills or hot flashes\n• Numbness or tingling sensations\n• Feeling like you have a lump in your throat\n• Persistent irritability</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoTextFour">We strongly suggest going through the following link for more information regarding the Symptoms, Diagnosis, Causes and Treatment Options of Generalised Anxiety Disorder: https://www.psycom.net/bookstore.anxiety.html\nDISCLAIMER: The creators of the app are not responsible for the information on the website.</string>
    <string name="breathingInfoTextView">This will guide you through some controlled breathing! \n Press Start to begin.</string>
    <string name="breathingStartStopButton">Start</string>
    <string name="crossItOffHeader">This strategy focuses on feeling like you are \"back in control\" of yourself.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextOne">Make a list of all the things you need to do that you\'re utterly bogged down with.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffSubtextOne">Important: Be sure to include something really, really easy! Like \"make a cup of tea\", \"do the hair\" or simply \"take your controller back to the console\".</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextTwo">Make the cup of tea (or the one of the other easy things you have chosen).</string>
    <string name="crossItOffNumberOne">1.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffNumberTwo">2.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffNumberThree">3.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextThree">Cross it off the list.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffSubtextThree">While doing this, try to be aware and be in the moment. Think to yourself \"one thing is done!\". This might sound simple, but it is a huge step for your brain.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffNumberFour">4.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextFour">Pick something else from the list (another easy one).</string>
    <string name="crossItOffNumberFive">5.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextFive">Do it!</string>
    <string name="crossItOffNumberSix">6.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextSix">Cross it off the list.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffFooter">When you get to a big one, you\'re already within a routine. It\'s all about getting back into control. \nBreak things down and keep crossing them off (don\'t miss this step!).</string>
    <string name="crossItOffCredits">Credits to Dr. Wolfgang Hoi for the information.</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsButton">Five Things Game</string>
    <string name="crossItOffButton">Cross It Off</string>
    <string name="controlledBreathingButton">Controlled Breathing</string>
    <string name="paintingButton">Painting</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoCredits">Information taken from https://www.psycom.net/depression.central.html</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoHeaderOne">Depression</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoTextOne">Depression is more than just feeling sad. Everyone feels upset or unmotivated from time to time, but depression is more serious. \nIt is a mood disorder characterized by prolonged feelings of sadness and loss of interest in daily activities. If these symptoms persist for a period of at least two weeks, it is considered a depressive episode.</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoHeaderTwo">Causes</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoTextThree">There is no one cause for depression, as it depends on a unique combination of an individual’s genetic makeup and environmental conditions. \nThere are many factors to take into account:</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoSubtextThree">• The brain’s physical structure or chemistry\n• History of depression in the family\n• History of other disorders (anxiety, post-traumatic stress disorder)\n• Stressful, traumatic events (abuse, financial issues, death of a loved one)\n• Hormone changes (menstrual cycles, pregnancy)\n• Certain medications (sleeping aids, blood pressure medication)</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoTextFour">We strongly suggest going through the following link for more information regarding the Types, Symptoms, Statistics and Treatment Options of Depression: https://www.psycom.net/depression.central.html\nDISCLAIMER: The creators of the app are not responsible for the information on the website.</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsHeader">Try to find 5 things that you can see and focus on that. \nThen focus on 5 things that you can feel and touch. \nFollow it up by 5 things that you can hear.</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsTextOne">It\'s all about distracting your brain from the stressful heating. \nAt this moment, you may already be distracted enough that the worst part is over. \nIt’s simple, easy to remember and also easy to do.</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsTextTwo">If the distraction doesn\'t kick in, try to make this addition - focus on 5 things that you can smell. \nOr try to get your hands on a smell. It distracts you immediately and is a good way to get out of your state.</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsTextThree">This game can also be expanded to thinking of animals, birds, colours, objects, movies, plants, foods, etc.</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsCredits">Credits to Dr. Wolfgang Hoi for the information.</string>
    <string name="biometricLoginButton">Login</string>
    <string name="mindfulnessToolHeaderOne">Bringing You Back on Track</string>
    <string name="mindfulnessToolTextOne">This technique can be practiced anywhere, any time, even as long as you like. \nSo just try this when you out for a walk, being in your room, riding on a train, or even during an exercise.</string>
    <string name="mindfulnessToolSubtextOne">• Take a minute or more (on purpose)\n• Try being fully aware of what is going on in and around you\n• Without any expectation or criticism (just a peaceful curiosity)\n• Including the thoughts which come and go right now (sensations, feelings)</string>
    <string name="mindfulnessToolSubtextTwo">It\'s all about \"switching off the auto-pilot\", noticing and watching your thoughts and feelings and waking up to the physical sensations of things. \nTogether with deep-belly breathing, paying attention to your body and training the mind to observe, focus and filter. \nThis is a great thing to do while running. If you don\'t like it that way, try to make a chocolate-eating while being mindful. That is a whole new experience.</string>
    <string name="mindfulnessToolCredits">Credits to Dr. Wolfgang Hoi for the information</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolCredits">Credits to Dr. Wolfgang Hoi and ReachOut for the information</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolHeaderOne">Steps to Problem Solving</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextOne">Try to browse through this list, if\n• you’re facing a difficult problem or decision.\n• you’re feeling overwhelmed by your options.\n• you want to learn how to make better decisions.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextTwo">8 steps to Problem Solving (credit to ReachOut)</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextThree">1. Define the problem. What exactly is going on? Sometimes a problem just seems too big to tackle. However, if you make a list and break it down into smaller parts that you can make a start on solving, it’ll feel more manageable.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextFour">2. Set some goals. Focus on the steps you can take to resolve things, rather than just thinking about what you’d like to happen. Maybe you wish you had more money. Make a list of all the ways you can save or earn more. It could mean walking to school rather than taking the bus, or applying for a part-time job.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextFive">3. Brainstorm possible solutions. Be creative and come up with as many solutions as you can think of. Some ideas may be way out there, but don’t worry about evaluating them yet. If you want to solve a conflict you’re having with your parents by escaping on a rainbow unicorn, write it down! Keep an open mind and list anything that comes to mind, plausible or not.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextSix">4. Rule out any obvious poor options. Okay, reality check. Evaluate your list of ideas and rule out the ones that are unrealistic or unhelpful. Bye-bye, rainbow unicorn. But how about trying to see things from your parents’ point of view? That option should probably stay on your list.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextSeven">5. Examine the consequences. Go through the options you’ve got left, and for each one write a list of their pros and cons.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextEight">6. Identify the best solutions. Now it’s time to make a decision. Look at your list of options, and pick out the ones that are most practical and helpful. There may be one obvious solution, or some might work in combination.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextNine">7. Put your solutions into practice. Have faith in yourself and make the commitment to try out one of your solutions.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextTen">8. How did it go? So, you tried it out. What happened? If you had more than one solution and the first didn’t work, move on to another one.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextEleven">If nothing works out, try to grab some of your coping skills, from your personal toolbox. If your situation is still interfering with your day-to-day life, it’s a good idea to get some professional help. \nLooking for support is never a bad thing. If the first person is not the right one, look further!</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolTextOne">Relaxing seems very easy, but is it really? \nA lot of people feel guilty for taking the time to relax or believe that they are \"wasting time\". Even worse, some think that they are being selfish.</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolTextTwo">Whether you are overwhelmed by work or personal things, taking time to relax is important. \nJust remember: you won’t have any resources (body or mind-wise) if you don\'t do it. \nIf you are too busy: just make the relaxation thing a routine, like an appointment with yourself!</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolHeaderTwo">Everyone\'s Personal Well-being \"Toolbox\"</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolTextThree">Every single one of us has one. Our own unique collection of ways to deal with life, to get to a state of mental well-being. \nIt’s made up of things that only you have. Eg. What kind of personality you have, strengths and weaknesses, if you like being alone, or with people. Relaxing is a part of it. \nWith the right tools, everyone can flourish!</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolTextFour">So think of it, what\'s in your toolbox? Are there some things missing, maybe others need a refill? Open for adjustments, additional aspects? \nMake a list or draw a toolbox, and put all the stuff in there, which is helping you.</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolSubtextThree">Example: try to use voice memos! Just think of it like \"check in with yourself tool\" like \"how am i feeling right now, how am i doing?\" Use some nice wordings and listen to it every day. Your brain benefits from that.</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolTextFive">Also, try to understand your stress. You probably already know what stresses you out. If not, it is easy to keep a \"stress diary\" at the end of every day.</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolSubtextFour">In the diary, describe what happened and whether you felt stressed after. Is it a mental fuzziness, or a feeling of tightness in your tummy? Pay attention to such questions. Chronic worry, Pessimism or Perfectionism can be causes of stress.</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolHeaderThree">Relaxation List</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolTextSix">Making lists is a very efficient way to relax or deal with stress, even if you are not \"a list person\" at all. Simply because the brain likes to bring things in order. So give it a try! \nThis can also be part of your well-being toolbox. \nSo, lets make a relaxation list, with things like:</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolSubtextFive">• going for a walk\n• having a bath\n• reading\n• meditating\n• playing a video game\n• chatting with friends\n• etc...</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolSubtextSix">You can refer to your relaxation list whenever you want to relax!</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolCredits">Credits to Dr. Wolfgang Hoi for the information</string>
    <string name="relaxingPaintingHeaderView">This activity will take you through a series of images that you can paint in or just clear and draw your own from scratch. \n We recommend putting on some relaxing music in the background while you do that. \n Note: The images drawn here can not be saved. This is a feature we are considering to implement in the future. If you want to draw something that can be saved, please use the notes feature or take a screenshot of your drawing when you\'re done.</string>
    <string name="paintingStartButton">Start Painting</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoHeaderOne">Help yourself</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoCredits">Information taken from https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/help-yourself/</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoTextOne">If you are in a crisis, you can help yourself by:</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextOne">• Finding a therapist or a support group: Speaking to someone can make you feel better and improve your mental health.\n\n• Building a support network: You don\'t have to deal with the crisis alone. People that you choose to confide in can help you. You can reach out via social networks, to your local community or to a close group of friends/family.\n\n• Use your support network: Express yourself to people you trust. Keep an open mind to the advice that others give, understand that its coming from a good place. Show appreciation for the people who are helping you get through these tough times.\n\n• Make a safety plan:</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextTwo">A safety plan is designed to guide you through a crisis. \n1. Recognize your personal warning signs: What thoughts, images, moods, situations, and behaviors indicate to you that a crisis may be developing? Write these down in your own words.\n2. Use your own coping strategies: List things that you can do on your own to help you not act on urges to harm yourself.\n3. Socialize with others who may offer support and distraction from the crisis: List people and social settings that may help take your mind off of difficult thoughts or feelings.\n4. Contact family members or friends who may help to resolve a crisis: Make a list of people who are supportive and who you feel you can talk to when under stress.\n5. Contact mental health professionals or agencies: Make a list of names, numbers and/or locations of clinicians, local emergency rooms, and crisis hotlines. \n6. Ensure your environment is safe: Have you thought of ways in which you might harm yourself? Work with a counselor to develop a plan to limit your access to these means.</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextThree">We suggest going through the following link for more in-depth explanation of the terms mentioned above: https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/help-yourself/\nDISCLAIMER: The creators of the app are not responsible for the information on the website.</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoHeaderTwo">Help Others</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoTextThree">How to identify if someone is at-risk:</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextFour">They use phrases like \"I\'m feeling suicidal, I\'m scared\", \"I need to talk/need help\", \"I don\'t know how I can keep going\", \"I feel hopeless\"</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoTextFour">How to support them:</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextFive">If you have identified somebody that is at risk of suicide, you should to approach them carefully. Try not to act as a mental healthcare professional and get them in touch with appropriate resources such as a professional or a helpline.</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoTextFive">If you think a person may be at imminent risk, call a suicide helpline or local emergency services.</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextSix">For more information, look at: https://yourlifecounts.org/, https://www.befrienders.org/general-information, https://www.befrienders.org/help-and-support, https://www.psycom.net/\nDISCLAIMER: The creators of the app are not responsible for the information on those websites.</string>
    <string name="vaultLoginButton">Open Vault</string>
    <string name="action_take_photo">Take Photo</string>
    <string name="action_choose_image">Choose Image</string>
    <string name="action_draw_image">Draw Image</string>
    <string name="action_record_audio">Record Audio</string>
    <string name="action_color_black">Black</string>
    <string name="action_color_red">Red</string>
    <string name="action_color_blue">Blue</string>
    <string name="action_color_yellow">Yellow</string>
    <string name="action_color_purple">Purple</string>
    <string name="action_color_lightblue">Light Blue</string>
    <string name="action_color_green">Green</string>
    <string name="action_color_lightgreen">Light Green</string>
    <string name="action_color_grey">Grey</string>
    <string name="action_color_orange">Orange</string>
    <string name="action_stroke_small">Stroke Small</string>
    <string name="action_stroke_medium">Stroke Medium</string>
    <string name="action_stroke_big">Stroke Big</string>
    <string name="action_eraser">Eraser</string>
    <string name="action_clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="action_contextbar_delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="action_contextbar_refresh">Refresh</string>
    <string name="action_contextbar_select_all">ALL</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoButton">About Anxiety</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoButton">About Depression</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoButton">About Suicidal Feelings</string>
    <string name="reachOutResourceButton">Reach Out</string>
    <string name="headspaceResourceButton">Headspace</string>
    <string name="stopBreatheThinkResourceButton"><![CDATA[Stop, Breathe & Think]]></string>
    <string name="samTheChatbotResourceButton">Sam the chatbot</string>
    <string name="befreindersWorldwideResourceButton">Befreinders Worldwide</string>
    <string name="psycomResourceButton">Ivan Goldberg\'s Psycom.net</string>
    <string name="yourLifeCountsResourceButton">Your Life Counts</string>
    <string name="suicidePreventionLifelineResourceButton">Suicide Prevention Lifeline.org (USA)</string>
    <string name="mindfullnessToolsButton">Mindfulness</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolsButton">Relaxation</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolsButton">Self Care: Problem Solving</string>
    <string name="imageViewItem">User-inserted image</string>
    <string name="action_save_record">Save Recording</string>
    <string name="action_delete_note_audio">DELETE</string>
    <string name="action_delete_edit_note">DELETE</string>
    <string name="action_void_edit_note">Send into the void.</string>
    <string name="action_delete_note_image">DELETE</string>
    <string name="action_save_paint">Save Drawing</string>
    <string name="action_delete_paint">Delete Drawing</string>
    <string name="action_next_image">Next Image</string>
    <string name="action_change_vault_pin">Change Pin</string>
    <string name="breathingStart">Start</string>
    <string name="breathingStop">Stop</string>
    <string name="breatheOut">Breathe Out.</string>
    <string name="breatheIn">Breathe In.</string>
    <string name="breathingGetReady">Get Ready.</string>
    <string name="noteNoTitle">No Title</string>
    <string name="noteNoBody">No Body</string>
    <string name="vaultLoginWrongPin">Wrong pin! Try again!</string>
    <string name="audioRecorderImageRecordContentDescription">Start recording image button</string>
    <string name="audioRecorderImageStopContentDescription">Stop recording image button.</string>
    <string name="audioRecorderImagePlayPauseContentDescription">Play or pause the recording playback image button.</string>
    <string name="audioViewImagePlayPauseContentDescription">Play or pause the audio playback image button.</string>
    <string name="noteImageImageViewContentDescription">Image inserted into the note.</string>
    <string name="vaultPinEntryHint">Pin...</string>
    <string name="audioCardImagePlayPauseContentDescription">Play or pause the audio playback image button.</string>
    <string name="action_discard_edit_note">Discard Changes</string>
</resources>
