<resources>
    <string name="action_change_vault_pin">Change Pin</string>
    <string name="action_choose_image">Choose Image</string>
    <string name="action_clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="action_color_black">Black</string>
    <string name="action_color_blue">Blue</string>
    <string name="action_color_green">Green</string>
    <string name="action_color_grey">Grey</string>
    <string name="action_color_lightblue">Light Blue</string>
    <string name="action_color_lightgreen">Light Green</string>
    <string name="action_color_orange">Orange</string>
    <string name="action_color_purple">Purple</string>
    <string name="action_color_red">Red</string>
    <string name="action_color_yellow">Yellow</string>
    <string name="action_contextbar_refresh">Refresh</string>
    <string name="action_contextbar_select_all">Select All</string>
    <string name="action_delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="action_delete_paint">Delete Drawing</string>
    <string name="action_discard_edit_note">Discard Changes</string>
    <string name="action_draw_image">Draw Image</string>
    <string name="action_eraser">Eraser</string>
    <string name="action_next_image">Next Image</string>
    <string name="action_record_audio">Record Audio</string>
    <string name="action_save_paint">Save Drawing</string>
    <string name="action_save_record">Save Recording</string>
    <string name="action_stroke_big">Stroke Big</string>
    <string name="action_stroke_medium">Stroke Medium</string>
    <string name="action_stroke_small">Stroke Small</string>
    <string name="action_take_photo">Take Photo</string>
    <string name="action_void_edit_note">Send into the void.</string>
    <string name="acton_cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoButton">About Anxiety</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoCredits">Information taken from https://www.psycom.net/bookstore.anxiety.html</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoHeaderOne">Generalised Anxiety Disorder</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoHeaderTwo">Symptoms</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoSubtextOne">Generalized Anxiety Disorder is different than having a phobia about something in the sense that people with GAD have an uneasy feeling about life in general. \nOften associated with feelings of dread or unease, you are in a state of constant worry over everything. There is no “off” switch. \nIf you are suffering from Generalized Anxiety Disorder, you are experiencing a constant state of worry – and you cannot avoid it, because life, in general, is causing you anxiety.</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoSubtextThree">• Perpetual state of constant worry\n• Inability to relax or enjoy quiet time\n• Muscle tightness or body aches\n• Feeling tense\n• Avoidance of stressful situations\n• Difficulty concentrating or focusing on things\n• No tolerance for uncertainty – needing to know what is going to happen and how it is going to happen\n• Constant feelings of dread or apprehension\n• Feeling overwhelmed and avoiding things or situations because of it\n• Intrusive thoughts of things that cause you to worry – even when you try to stop thinking about them\n• Feeling like you can’t control your emotions and constant worry – nothing you do helps you to relax\n• Not being able to sleep at all or to sleep well because you are in a constant state of worry\n• Feeling jumpy, on edge, or restless\n• Stomach upset – including nausea and diarrhea\n• Fatiguing easily\n• Heart palpitations – feeling like your heart is racing\n• Trembles or shakes\n• Sweating and dry mouth\n• Having difficulty breathing and/or feeling like you are choking\n• Feeling lightheaded or dizzy\n• Cold chills or hot flashes\n• Numbness or tingling sensations\n• Feeling like you have a lump in your throat\n• Persistent irritability</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoSubtextTwo">Studies have shown that if you are living with Generalized Anxiety Disorder, you are more likely to also suffer from other mental health issues and ailments. \nCommon conditions that are associated with Generalized Anxiety Disorder include depression(https://www.psycom.net/depression.central.html), irritable bowel syndrome, stress, attention deficit hyperactivity disorder(https://www.psycom.net/adult-adhd/), and substance abuse(https://www.psycom.net/depression.central.substance.html).</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoTextFour">We strongly suggest going through the following link for more information regarding the Symptoms, Diagnosis, Causes and Treatment Options of Generalised Anxiety Disorder: https://www.psycom.net/bookstore.anxiety.html\nDISCLAIMER: The creators of the app are not responsible for the information on the website.</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoTextOne">If you find yourself in constant worry over anything and everything in your life, even when there should be no cause for concern, you might be suffering from Generalized Anxiety Disorder.</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoTextThree">Some of the symptoms of GAD are:</string>
    <string name="anxietyInfoTextTwo">Generalized Anxiety Disorder is one of the most common anxiety disorders. While it can occur at any point of life, the most common points of onset occur between childhood and middle age. \nIf you are a woman, you are twice as likely to suffer from Generalized Anxiety Disorder than men.</string>
    <string name="app_name">Kind Companion</string>
    <string name="audioCardImagePlayPauseContentDescription">Play or pause the audio playback image button.</string>
    <string name="audioRecorderImagePlayPauseContentDescription">Play or pause the recording playback image button.</string>
    <string name="audioRecorderImageRecordContentDescription">Start recording image button</string>
    <string name="audioRecorderImageStopContentDescription">Stop recording image button.</string>
    <string name="audioViewImagePlayPauseContentDescription">Play or pause the audio playback image button.</string>
    <string name="befreindersWorldwideResourceButton">Befreinders Worldwide</string>
    <string name="biometricLoginButton">Login</string>
    <string name="breatheIn">Breathe In.</string>
    <string name="breatheOut">Breathe Out.</string>
    <string name="breathingGetReady">Get Ready.</string>
    <string name="breathingInfoTextView">This will guide you through some controlled breathing! \n Press Start to begin.</string>
    <string name="breathingStart">Start</string>
    <string name="breathingStartStopButton">Start</string>
    <string name="breathingStop">Stop</string>
    <string name="controlledBreathingButton">Controlled Breathing</string>
    <string name="crossItOffButton">Cross It Off</string>
    <string name="crossItOffFooter">When you get to a bigger task, you will already be feeling like you are back in control of your life. Break tasks down to smaller ones and keep crossing them off (dont forget to do this!).</string>
    <string name="crossItOffHeader">When you feel like you are spiraling out of control and not getting anything done, use this technique!</string>
    <string name="crossItOffSubtextOne">Important: Be sure to include things that are easy to do! Like \"drink a glass of water\" or \"store away the remote\".</string>
    <string name="crossItOffSubtextThree">As you do this, be aware of the fact that you are finishing a task! Think to yourself, "one thing is done". This is a huge step for your brain.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextFive">Do it!</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextFour">Pick something else from the list. Another easy task.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextOne">Make a list of all the things you feel bogged down with.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextSix">Cross it off the list.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextThree">Cross the task off the list.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffTextTwo">Get a glass of water and drink it, or any other easy thing on the list.</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoButton">About Depression</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoCredits">Information taken from https://www.psycom.net/depression.central.html</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoHeaderOne">Depression</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoHeaderTwo">Causes</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoSubtextThree">• The brain’s physical structure or chemistry\n• History of depression in the family\n• History of other disorders (anxiety, post-traumatic stress disorder)\n• Stressful, traumatic events (abuse, financial issues, death of a loved one)\n• Hormone changes (menstrual cycles, pregnancy)\n• Certain medications (sleeping aids, blood pressure medication)</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoTextFour">We strongly suggest going through the following link for more information regarding the Types, Symptoms, Statistics and Treatment Options of Depression: https://www.psycom.net/depression.central.html\nDISCLAIMER: The creators of the app are not responsible for the information on the website.</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoTextOne">Depression is more than just feeling sad. Everyone feels upset or unmotivated from time to time, but depression is more serious. \nIt is a mood disorder characterized by prolonged feelings of sadness and loss of interest in daily activities. If these symptoms persist for a period of at least two weeks, it is considered a depressive episode.</string>
    <string name="depressionInfoTextThree">There is no one cause for depression, as it depends on a unique combination of an individual’s genetic makeup and environmental conditions. \nThere are many factors to take into account:</string>
    <string name="fifthMainButton">Vault</string>
    <string name="firstMainButton">Calm Down Quickly</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsButton">Five Things Game</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsHeader">If you are ever panicking or feeling anxious, this technique can help calm yourself down.</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsTextOne">This will help distract your brain from the anxiety and the panic. Even with those 3 steps, you might already be calm. It is a very simple technique.</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsTextThree">This game can also be expanded to thinking of animals, birds, colours, objects, movies, plants, foods, etc.</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsTextTwo">If the distraction doesn\'t kick in, try to make this addition - focus on 5 things that you can smell. \nOr try to get your hands on a smell. It distracts you immediately and is a good way to get out of your state.</string>
    <string name="fourthMainButton">Reminders</string>
    <string name="frontPageWelcomeMessage">Welcome to Kind Companion!</string>
    <string name="headspaceResourceButton">Headspace</string>
    <string name="imageViewItem">User-inserted image</string>
    <string name="mindfullnessToolsButton">Mindfulness</string>
    <string name="mindfulnessToolSubtextOne">• Take a minute or more, on purpose.\n• Try to be aware of everything that is going on in and around you.\n• Don\'t expect anything, just be curious.\n• Focus on the thoughts, sensations and feelings that come and go.</string>
    <string name="mindfulnessToolSubtextTwo">It is about breaking your current flow of things, taking a while and making yourself aware of the sensations of the things around you. \nCombining this with deep breaths can help you focus more. \nIf you dont think you can make the time out for it, just try to do it while eating!</string>
    <string name="mindfulnessToolTextOne">This technique can be practiced anytime anywhere, for as long as you like. \nYou can do this while you are doing exercise or just sitting in your room.</string>
    <string name="new_note">New Note</string>
    <string name="noteImageImageViewContentDescription">Image inserted into the note.</string>
    <string name="noteNoBody">No Body</string>
    <string name="noteNoTitle">No Title</string>
    <string name="note_entry_hint">Enter your note…</string>
    <string name="note_entry_title_hint">Title</string>
    <string name="number_five">5.</string>
    <string name="number_four">4.</string>
    <string name="number_one">1.</string>
    <string name="number_six">6.</string>
    <string name="number_three">3.</string>
    <string name="number_two">2.</string>
    <string name="paintingButton">Painting</string>
    <string name="paintingStartButton">Start Painting</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolCredits">Credits to ReachOut for the information</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolHeaderOne">Steps to Problem Solving</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextEight">6. Identify the best solutions. Now it’s time to make a decision. Look at your list of options, and pick out the ones that are most practical and helpful. There may be one obvious solution, or some might work in combination.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextEleven">If nothing works, try some of your other coping mechanisms. If you still feel bogged down, it is a good idea to <a href="https://au.reachout.com/mental-health-issues/professional-help">seek professional help</a>! \nLooking for support is never a bad thing!</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextFive">3. Brainstorm possible solutions. Be creative and come up with as many solutions as you can think of. Some ideas may be way out there, but don’t worry about evaluating them yet. If you want to solve a conflict you’re having with your parents by escaping on a rainbow unicorn, write it down! Keep an open mind and list anything that comes to mind, plausible or not.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextFour">2. Set some goals. Focus on the steps you can take to resolve things, rather than just thinking about what you’d like to happen. Maybe you wish you had more money. Make a list of all the ways you can save or earn more. It could mean walking to school rather than taking the bus, or applying for a part-time job.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextNine">7. Put your solutions into practice. Have faith in yourself and make the commitment to try out one of your solutions.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextOne">Try to browse through this list, if\n• you’re facing a difficult problem or decision.\n• you’re feeling overwhelmed by your options.\n• you want to learn how to make better decisions.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextSeven">5. Examine the consequences. Go through the options you’ve got left, and for each one write a list of their pros and cons.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextSix">4. Rule out any obvious poor options. Okay, reality check. Evaluate your list of ideas and rule out the ones that are unrealistic or unhelpful. Bye-bye, rainbow unicorn. But how about trying to see things from your parents’ point of view? That option should probably stay on your list.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextTen">8. How did it go? So, you tried it out. What happened? If you had more than one solution and the first didn’t work, move on to another one.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextThree">1. Define the problem. What exactly is going on? Sometimes a problem just seems too big to tackle. However, if you make a list and break it down into smaller parts that you can make a start on solving, it’ll feel more manageable.</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolTextTwo">8 steps to Problem Solving</string>
    <string name="problemSolvingToolsButton">Self Care: Problem Solving</string>
    <string name="psycomResourceButton">Ivan Goldberg\'s Psycom.net</string>
    <string name="reachOutResourceButton">Reach Out</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolHeaderThree">Relaxation List</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolSubtextFive">• going for a walk\n• taking a bath\n• meditating\n• listening to music\n• etc&#8230;</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolSubtextSix">You can refer to your relaxation list whenever you want to relax!</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolTextOne">Remember: its always okay to relax. No need to feel guilty about it. It helps the body and mind loosen up. You should try to make it a routine.</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolTextSix">You can make a list of things that help you relax! This will work even if you are not a list person. \nIt can have things like:</string>
    <string name="relaxationToolsButton">Relaxation</string>
    <string name="relaxingPaintingHeaderView">This activity will take you through a series of images that you can paint in or just clear and draw your own from scratch. \n We recommend putting on some relaxing music in the background while you do that.</string>
    <string name="samTheChatbotResourceButton">Sam the chatbot</string>
    <string name="save">SAVE</string>
    <string name="secondMainButton">Deal With Anxiety</string>
    <string name="sixthMainButton">Settings</string>
    <string name="stopBreatheThinkResourceButton"><![CDATA[Stop, Breathe & Think]]></string>
    <string name="suicideInfoButton">About Suicidal Feelings</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoCredits">Information taken from https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/help-yourself/</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoHeaderOne">Help Yourself</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoHeaderTwo">Help Others</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextFive">If you have identified somebody that is at risk of suicide, you should to approach them carefully. Try not to act as a mental healthcare professional and get them in touch with appropriate resources such as a professional or a helpline.</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextFour">They use phrases like \"I\'m feeling suicidal, I\'m scared\", \"I need to talk/need help\", \"I don\'t know how I can keep going\", \"I feel hopeless\"</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextOne">• Finding a therapist or a support group: Speaking to someone can make you feel better and improve your mental health.\n\n• Building a support network: You don\'t have to deal with the crisis alone. People that you choose to confide in can help you. You can reach out via social networks, to your local community or to a close group of friends/family.\n\n• Use your support network: Express yourself to people you trust. Keep an open mind to the advice that others give, understand that its coming from a good place. Show appreciation for the people who are helping you get through these tough times.\n\n• Make a safety plan:</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextSix">For more information, look at: https://yourlifecounts.org/, https://www.befrienders.org/general-information, https://www.befrienders.org/help-and-support, https://www.psycom.net/\nDISCLAIMER: The creators of the app are not responsible for the information on those websites.</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextThree">We suggest going through the following link for more in-depth explanation of the terms mentioned above: https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/help-yourself/\nDISCLAIMER: The creators of the app are not responsible for the information on the website.</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoSubtextTwo">A safety plan is designed to guide you through a crisis. \n1. Recognize your personal warning signs: What thoughts, images, moods, situations, and behaviors indicate to you that a crisis may be developing? Write these down in your own words.\n2. Use your own coping strategies: List things that you can do on your own to help you not act on urges to harm yourself.\n3. Socialize with others who may offer support and distraction from the crisis: List people and social settings that may help take your mind off of difficult thoughts or feelings.\n4. Contact family members or friends who may help to resolve a crisis: Make a list of people who are supportive and who you feel you can talk to when under stress.\n5. Contact mental health professionals or agencies: Make a list of names, numbers and/or locations of clinicians, local emergency rooms, and crisis hotlines. \n6. Ensure your environment is safe: Have you thought of ways in which you might harm yourself? Work with a counselor to develop a plan to limit your access to these means.</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoTextFive">If you think a person may be at imminent risk, call a suicide helpline or local emergency services.</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoTextFour">How to support them:</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoTextOne">If you are in a crisis, you can help yourself by:</string>
    <string name="suicideInfoTextThree">How to identify if someone is at-risk:</string>
    <string name="suicidePreventionLifelineResourceButton">Suicide Prevention Lifeline.org (USA)</string>
    <string name="thirdMainButton">Useful Information</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">SettingsActivity</string>
    <string name="vaultLoginButton">Open Vault</string>
    <string name="vaultLoginWrongPin">Wrong pin! Try again!</string>
    <string name="vaultPinEntryHint">Pin&#8230;</string>
    <string name="yourLifeCountsResourceButton">Your Life Counts</string>
    <string name="relaxingPaintingTextOne">Note: The images drawn here can not be saved. This is a feature we are considering to implement in the future. If you want to draw something that can be saved, please use the notes feature or take a screenshot of your drawing when you\'re done. \nChanging the screen orientation mid-paint might also cause your progress to be lost.</string>
    <string name="crossItOffSubHeader">This can work even if you are not a list person.</string>
    <string name="applicationInfoTextOne">Kind Companion has been developed in an attempt to help people deal with everyday anxiety. \nApp is currently in beta and will be getting more features soon.</string>
    <string name="applicationInfoTextTwo">Developed by Shivi Vats. \nSpecial thanks to MMag. Wolfgang Hoi for his advice and guidance.</string>
    <string name="applicationInfoTextThree">Version 0.1</string>
    <string name="applicationInfoSubtextOne">Shivi Vats can be found at: \nhttp://www.shivivats.io \nhttps://github.com/shivivats \nhttps://zarroc.itch.io</string>
    <string name="applicationCreditsHeaderOne">Resources Credits</string>
    <string name="applicationCreditsTextOne">Most images for the Relaxing Painting activity taken from Pixabay.com. Base icon image also taken from Pixabay.com. \nAll images fall under the Pixabay license: https://pixabay.com/service/license/.</string>
    <string name="applicationCreditsTextTwo">Special thanks to users 13smok, OpenClipart-Vectors, No-longer-here, BartuLenka, Zizitom, KaylinArt, RichardsDrawings, Carmealex, coloringcuties, waldryano, mohamed_hassan and anarosadebastiani for the images.</string>
    <string name="applicationCreditsSubtextOne">Also thank you to Karen Arnold from publicdomainpictures.net</string>
    <string name="fiveThingsSecondHeader">Sense 5 things that you can see around you and focus on them.\nThen focus on 5 things you can feel and touch.\nThen 5 things that you can hear.</string>
    <string name="offMyChestHeader">If you want to get something off your chest, the \"Send into the void\" option for the notes can help send your thoughts out for them to disappear forever. \nThe note can be accessed via the Reminder or Vault pages.</string>
    <string name="offMyChestReminderButton">Open Reminders</string>
    <string name="offMyChestVaultButton">Open Vault</string>
    <string name="applicationInfoTextFour"><a href="https://medium.com/@shivivats7/kind-companion-privacy-policy-b9ad4d1a1d0f">Privacy Policy</a></string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
</resources>
